yo what up scope he's happy Friday
everybody happy Friday we'll wait for a
few people to get in here look you can
see her broken metrics they're broken
broken metrics wait for a few people to
show up welcome to the comma a periscope
it is it's not a scope you Friday we're
here today to talk about the comma pedal
I'm this Claud you know now I'm in a
good mood today I'm in a good mood today
but but Subaru in the chat ban yo pedal
pedal pedal pedal yo yo yo what up okay
guys I have I have a new piece of
hardware to announce I have a new piece
of hardware it's right here in my other
hand let's wait till we get 60 people we
can do 60
let's get 60 people in here and then I
will show you all the hardware for kamma
pedal we got 50 for your base station DS
not ready yet your your your base
station DS not ready yet no come on we
got 56 come on let's get it up to 60 and
then you guys can see it 59 we're almost
there 60 okay welcome welcome welcome
check it out the pedal is quality just
like the sign says okay so here I am on
the comment
this is the world's first comma pedal
super-strong glue holding it together it
looks like an Apple charger look at that
thing comes in light blue check it out
now remember comma petals are not for
sale we're gonna open source them
sometime next week whenever Eddie
finishes them ah here's a petal so this
is a pedal it's a pedal from an Acura
ILX the way the column petal works is
you plug it into your existing pedal and
it makes your pedal digital so here's a
pedal that's a common pedal and I will
just plug this in right here and now we
are ready to come a pedal this USB
connector is used for debugging and
updating the , pedal firmware of course
it has firmware and this Ethernet
connector is the same fake Ethernet
connector that's on the giraffe's what
cars work with it it should be all
Honda's we think it's all Honda's well
we don't actually know if common pedals
work yet we just got this from the
hardware division right now so cardona
are gonna go out to the Acura and we're
gonna try to make it work um so of
course the Civic needs it a lot less the
Civic needs it a lot less then then the
other stuff because the Civic can
already do stop and go but the common
pedal adds stop and go to the rest of
the Honda's and gives you better more
precise gas pedal control less pulsing
super precision from the common panel in
fact it's just as good as you pressing
the pedal widow the Kama steer comes out
so let's go to the here with Ricardo got
108 people are excited about the column
pedal oh come on fella buzz right so
we're gonna go to the car right now and
we're gonna try it out and we're gonna
see if it works this is completely
untested the codes not tested it is
merged though it's upstreams now you can
check it out on github karma a I pedal
how's the lawyers going
want to say hi this scope is real quick
alright Eddie we're showing the scope is
a comma pedal we're gonna go test it for
the first time ever what do you think
right it's it needs a little bit to seal
properly yeah huh too bad you can see oh
you want to see the board no I mean -
bet you can see why so mom yeah Oh
the car is beautiful I advise looks like
an eye you know what I was looking at
our car I was looking at our car garage
those white USB cables are gross can
confirm does work on apologize to that
one look that door works
you have the good old Acura then you go
to get an iPad charger all right what's
my gamer - IRA you you're you asking
about Subaru your band bro there's
definitely a connector pedal you guys
could definitely get a common pedal yep
you asked about Subaru and you asked for
my phone number bad band I better I
better movie with savage today Savage
right so the actor is disgusting and we
haven't gotten it washed in a while
we're gonna do that today but it rained
and the car washes are closed when it
rains all right so we already have it
Ethernet wire down there don't we do you
know if that's actually like plugged in
to the right stuff I think so cool what
does pedal do panel gives you super
precise digital control over your gas
pedal um you can do the same thing with
an ECU mod but hardware team is better
than car hacking team all right
um it's also more Universal so here's
your column pedal up check the top
connector first cuz we're not actually
sure if that fits
yeah that doesn't fit we're gonna have
to stop the scope e-everyone gonna have
to fix it yeah check out this is my
display childen my acura up this is a
commis maze you can buy this on shop
comedy yard when they're not out of
stock this is a gray panda you can buy
that on shop and come down I would saw
this stock it's an old granite before we
have the proper thing that's actually
terrible mounting the antenna don't
learn from us um here's a neon what
about brake we already have really good
brake control actually how the brake
digital brake control is really good
what's just surprising since the gas
smells already digital I don't know why
they don't just give you good control
but they don't so that's why we built
the common pedal you can check out my
yarn
check out my gear and we save them in my
black Aeons for you guys doing any
meetups we really do
meetups not will Phelps bro bro bro
you're gonna be bad no way to hack into
guys people control we could hack it but
I'm lazy you want to see it you want to
see the calm pedal in person it's not
that great we are gonna open source the
comic pedal the firm was early open
source you guys can go to github come AI
Panda and you guys can check it out
this open source to me have you is a
laptop running ricardo's trying to get
the wires plugged into the comic peddle
comic pedals are new anyway for
simulation with the github Oh failure
pedal hardware um so if it truly
catastrophic lis fails then you will
just lose acceleration on your car it's
pretty safe basically yeah your car
doesn't accelerate put your hands on
pull to the side of the road yeah so
what's that is that is that Q is that as
well if you lose if you lose
acceleration yeah it's QM yeah yeah I'm
here with Ricardo new calibration not
coming with HDR though new calibration
is in progress
we've actually done calibration
correctly now wait no no you want to put
this one into the top yeah the one that
sticks out more gets plugged into the
wire does it does it not that can you
fix the slow acceleration on the Civic
can we fix that software yeah we gotta
fix that the software I complained about
it - it was bad anyone who reminds me of
will Phelps is bad calibration soon TM
eventually TM is like never soon TM as
is maybe yeah I got an already on what
is on pilot getting HDR after after
Scheffer plus I think that's gonna be
Andi sprint next week will come a pedal
also work with Toyota
do the Toyotas with hacking because the
Toyotas don't really separate the gas in
the brake you just feed them
acceleration is that true yes yeah and
like I mean like on a Prius how much
sense does it really make to like Jack
the pedal and you don't want the pedal
you want acceleration control shiver'd
plus usage versus open pilot usage
that's a very secret number very secret
we're doing we don't have for
pussies is it it doesn't fit I'll try a
little bet if you want to if you want to
take the phone and then if the common
pedal doesn't fit we'll have to send it
back to hardware and we'll have to come
on the periscope later tonight once we
have it fixed all right
here's a skull piece yeah I don't know
any thought that just by clicking that
it would floor Thursday I think this is
the part coming I think it's this part
okay on the other one we totally had to
all rights copies well guess what
we will be back later tonight to show
you a fully operational comma pedal
we're gonna we're gonna return this one
we're gonna return it to comment down a
I slash shop you guys should go there
and buy things today is a great day to
buy things tomorrow's great day to buy
things yesterday was also a great day to
fight us